major work

automotive camera
Fixed Focal Lens
zoom lens

calibration

Due to the high maturity of the lens and image sensor markets, there are a large number of
lenses with different optical features and sensors with different electrical characteristics.
Some modules of the ISP cannot automatically compensate for these features.Thus, we have some calibration in some moudules;
such as LSC, AWB, CCM and CLUT. There are some difference among chip platform. 


There are a serials modules in pipeline.
In linear mode, image quality emphasizes on the following dimensions: luminance, definition,
noise, distinctness, and color reproduction. For luminance, the modules include automatic
exposure (AE), dynamic range control (DRC), and shading correction.
For definition and noise, the modules include demosaic, sharpen before 3DNR
For distinctness, the modules include gamma, local dynamic contrast improvement (LDCI),
dehaze, and dynamic range control (DRC).
For color reproduction, the modules include automatic white balance (AWB), color correction matrix (CCM)
color lookup table (CLUT), and chrominance adjustment (CA)
The procedure of calibrating the sensor and lens must be performed by strictly following the flowchart


-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
The AE algorithms include the iris first algorithm, shutter first algorithm, and gain first algorithm. 
The AE algorithm consists of the AE statistical module and AE algorithm Firmware (providing
the AE control policy). The AE statistical module collects statistics on the luminance of the sensor input data. 
The AE algorithm principle is that the input image statistics are obtained in real time and compared with the target luminance. 
The sensor exposure time, gain, and lens iris are dynamically adjusted to ensure that the actual luminance is close to the target luminance.

The spectral components of visible light vary according to the color temperature. The white
objects have a red cast at a low color temperature or have a blue cast at a high color
temperature. Human eyes can identify the actual object color based on brain reflections. The
AWB algorithm is used to reduce the impacts on the actual object color exerted by external
illuminants. This ensures that the captured color information is converted into the
information without color cast under an ideal illuminant.

Color temperature: It is defined based on the absolute black body. When the radiation of
an illuminant is the same as that of the absolute black body in the visible area, the
temperature of the absolute black body is the color temperature.

WB: The response to the white color in the sensor has a blue or red cast under the
illuminants with different color temperatures. The WB algorithm is used to adjust the
strength of R, G, and B channels to obtain the actual white color.

The AWB module consists of the WB statistical module and AWB policy control algorithm
firmware. The WB statistical module of the ISP determines whether each pixel output by the
sensor meets the white pixel requirements specified by users, and calculates the average
values of the R, G, and B channels for all the pixels that meet the requirements.

The picture can be divided into M x N (M rows and N columns) zones. The AWB module can
output the average R, G, and B values of each zone as well as those of the entire picture, and
the number of white pixels involved in statistics.


The policy of AE algorithm is base of Image. In policy of my AE algorithm, sensor shutter and gain are computed directly according to statistics. In actual application, it is more quicker and stable than others. How to get the shutter and gain value? This is the core concept. In theory, when illumination is constant,  the image brightness is proportional to the aperture, shutter and gain. For example, shutter double, image brightness double. In the actual calculation, shutter is computed in rows, and gain is computed by gain table. When we know the ratio of the current brightness to the target brightness, means, we get the ratio need to adjust. Usually, the shutter and gain route is defined  in AE algorithm created. There are different mode in exposure route. For example,  considering the noise, we use shutter first route.  Considering object moving, we use gain first route. After we get the ratio need to adjust, we usually change ratio into DB.
 
 



The white objects have a red cast at a low color temperature or have a blue cast at a high color temperature. Human eyes can identify the actual object color based on brain reflections. The AWB algorithm is used to //
Global grey world. My AWB algorithm is based on Planck's law or Blackbody radiation law.  under ideal conditions, the pixel of Rgain and  Bgain value in  different color temperature can be connected to  a smooth curve. We call it as Planck curve.
The AWB algorithm consists of the WB statistical module and AWB policy control algorithm firmware. 
The WB statistical module of the ISP determines whether each pixel output by the
sensor meets the white pixel requirements specified by users, and calculates the average
values of the R, G, and B channels for all the pixels that meet the requirements.
The major work of WB policy is choose the zones and assign weights for the zones. How to choose zones?
Firstly, exclude the extreme zone, such as  abnormal brightness or Rgain.  Then,  if the white zones far away from the planck curve., discard the zones. How to assign the weight for zones? The first rule,  the closer with planck curve, more weight for the zone.   Second rule, assign weight According to the illumination. Such as 5000K~6000K. 

The picture can be divided into M x N (M rows and N columns) zones. The AWB module can
output the average R, G, and B values of each zone as well as those of the entire picture, and
the number of white pixels involved in statistics. 


For example, Gaussian low-pass filtering computes a weighted average of pixel values in the neighborhood, in which the weights decrease with distance from the neighborhood center. The noise values that corrupt these nearby pixels are mutually less correlated than the signal values, so noise is averaged away while signal is preserved. 
Bilateral filtering is a simple  for edge-preserving smoothing. It also computes a weighted average of pixel values in the neighborhood. But what is different from Gaussian filtering? Bilateral filtering is not only considering the Euclidean distance between pixels, but also considering the value between pixels. At the flat region, the value of pixels are closed, then the weight is close to 1. 
	

maximal variance between clusters  OSTU
图像二值化 image  binarization

特征描述子： feature descriptor 
Harris 角点检测

RANSAC为Random Sample Consensus的缩写
欧式距离：Euclidean distance
Matching points


• Let's look for corners. Since corners represents a variation in the gradient in the image, we will look for this "variation".
• Consider a grayscale image I. We are going to sweep a window w(x,y) (with displacements u in the x direction and v in the right direction) I and will calculate the variation of intensity.

